本字幕由 PTT同志影视作品板 2013重新校稿
原字幕取自网路资源  仅供学习 禁用任何商业盈利行为
校稿：hahanjia、aaa、mohiwa
同志亦凡人 Queer As Folk S01E19
你不接吗？
Are you going to get that?
干嘛
What?
什麽时候
When?
好  我会去
Yeah, I'll be there.
还好吗
Everything okay?
是的  有人挂了
Yeah, some- body died.
天啊
Oh my... oh my god!
我很抱歉
I'm really sorry.
我们也许该走了
M-maybe we should go.
是
Yeah.
谁让你们停了
Who told you to stop?
好  你们会想要跟谁上床
Okay. Who would you sleep with?
-教授呢　还是吉利安  　　　　　-这还用说
-The professor or Gilligan?    -Easy.
当然是教授  他声音好有磁性
Professor. He had that deep voice,
还有烫得平整的衬衫
Those perfectly pressed shirts.
你也不想想  他在那岛上
Yeah, how do you suppose he found a good cleaner
要怎麽找乾洗店
on that island?
我在匹兹堡都找不到
I can't find one in Pittsburgh.
弗雷德·弗林斯通 还是巴尼·伦博？
Fred Flintstone, Barney Rubble?
交往还是上床
Mmm, we're talking a relationship or just sex?
就一夜情
Hmm, one night only.
那我选弗雷德
I have to go with Fred.
他是熊男
He's a total bear.
罗普先生还是福莱先生
Okay. Mr. Roper or Mr. Furley?
真难选
Mmmm. Tough one.
我选罗普
I'm going to go with Roper
我讨厌别人穿太花俏
But only because I have an aversion to loud colours
只有我可以
On anyone except me.
我要咖啡
I need coffee.
看来某个
Oh, someone was up
干到半夜的人也起床了
fucking until the wee hours.
他有我可爱吗
Was he cuter than me?
你在这干什麽
What are you doing here?
我在第一节课前加个班
Oh, I picked up an extra shift before first period.
存点钱好参加白色派对
I'm saving up to go to the white party.
天  难道你俩养不起他吗
My, my, aren't you two raising him well?
谁明天要去看麦特·戴蒙的新片
Anyone want to go see that new Matt Damon movie tomorrow?
我昨天
I was, uh,
在聊天室看到消息
reading in a chat room last night that
据说会有露屌的画面哦
there's a dick shot in it.
很短  但总比没有好
It's brief, but nonetheless...
屌耶
Dick!
是啊  当然
Yeah, totally.
-我去  　　　　　　　-你呢
- Yeah. I'm there.   - What about you?
我不行  我家里有事
I can't. I have family stuff.
怎麽  你姐姐又和前夫打架了吗
W-why? Your sister fighting with her ex-husband again?
我爸去世了
My dad died.
什麽
Your dad?
什麽时候
When?
昨天
Yesterday.
我很难过
I'm really sorry.
他病得不轻  差不多是时候了
Well, he was sick. It was time.
但那是你爸
Yeah, but he's your dad.
我说了我没事
I said I'm fine.
要是我爸死了  我会不知所措
If my dad died, I don't know what I'd do.
我也是
Me either.
-他多大年纪了  　　-60岁
- How old was he?  -60.
-真够老了　　-60岁才不老
- Ancient.   - 60's not ancient.
据说现在的孩子能长命百岁呢
They say kids who are born today are going to live to be past 100.
你能想像活到一百岁了还做爱？
Hey, can you imagine having sex when you're 100?
不  现在我都想不到
No. I can't imagine doing it now.
看凯文·切斯
Check out Kevin Chase.
-你觉得怎样  　　　　　-帅毙了
- What do you think?   - Total hottie.
他还有个大屌
And he's got a huge dick.
-你怎麽知道  　　　　-体育课上的意外收获
- How do you know?   - Gym class does have its perks.
克雷格·马修斯呢
What about Craig Matthews?
呃  他有粉刺
Huh-uh. He's got acne.
对  但他屁股很翘
Yeah, but a hot ass.
那
What about...
格兰·里维斯呢
Glen Reeves?
他还可以
He's okay.
就还可以吗
Just okay?
实际上  他是挺可爱的
Actually he's... he's kind of adorable.
耶  他很可爱
Yeah, he's totally adorable.
而且我可从他身上嗅到Gay味
And you know, I've always gotten this closeted-homo vibe from him.
我打赌  要是啤酒够多
I bet with enough beers
音乐够劲
and the right music,
-我们绝对可以干上       　　-胡扯
-We'd totally be doing it.  -No way.
我还可以吗
How'd I do?
你看起来棒透了
You looked great out there.
-怎麽回事  　　　　　-骗到你了吧
-What's going on?   - Gotcha!
-你们两个认识吧？  　　　　　　　　 -当然
-You two know each other, right?    -Sure.
-怎麽样？   　　　-还好
-How's it going?  -Okay.
晚上到我家看书吧
Oh, want to come to my place tonight and study?
喔　我要去贾斯汀家
Uh, actually I was supposed to study at Justin's.
但没关系
But if it's cool,
下次再约？
Could I take a rain check?
没问题
Sure.
我上课要迟到了
I'm going to be late for class.
干  今晚人好多
Fuck! It's a hot crowd in here tonight.
布莱恩  你不该来这里的
Brian, you shouldn't be here.
那我要去哪
Yeah, where should I be?
去你妈家啊？  准备你爸爸的葬礼？
At your mom's? Planning your dad's funeral?
其实他算是下葬了
He's practi- cally buried.
看到你的夜生活 风雨无歇
Well, it's reas- suring to know that neither rain nor snow
真让人欣慰
can keep you from your appointed rounds.
一以贯之可是难得的美德
Consistency's a rare virtue.
特别是在这事事充满变数的年代
Especially in these uncertain times.
听着  如果你有任何需要
Look, if you need anything...
-比如跑杂事  　　　　　　　-打电话
- Like running errands...  - Making calls...
不用你们操心
It's taken care of.
你在干什麽
What are you doing?
我来找牌搭
I-I'm looking for a fourth for bridge.
都什麽时候了  还想着这档子事
How can you even think about sex right now?
死亡让我性奋了
Ah, death gives you a real hard-on.
我送你回家
Look, let me take you home.
老天  布莱恩  你爸爸刚去世
Jesus, Brian, your dad just died!
你怎麽还能想着让别人帮你口交
How can you think about getting your dick sucked?
这是我的悲伤心理治疗法
This is my grief counsellor.
他现在算是你男友吗
Is he actually your boyfriend now or something?
-算是吧  　　-多谢你告诉我
- I guess.   - Thanks for telling me.
你一整年都和一个29岁的老男人上床
You've been fucking some 29-year-old guy the whole year.
我就不能找个男朋友吗
Why can't I see someone too?
-你们在一起多久了  　　　　　　　　　　　-一个月吧
- So how long have you guys been...?     -Oh, about a month.
有一天在英文课的下课时间  我们开始聊起
One day after English class we started talking
《嘉莉妹妹》这本书
about "Sister Carrie" and
是多麽震撼的悲剧故事
how awesome and tragic it is.
很快我们就开始互传简讯
Before I knew it, we were instant- messaging each other
基本上每个晚上都在传
Practically every night.
我们还是最好的朋友吧
Well, we're still best friends, right?
-算是吧  　　-不是吗
-I guess.    -Well, aren't we?
你们上床了吗
Have you guys done the nasty yet?
不关你的事
None of your business.
拜托  我什麽都告诉你了
Oh, come on. I tell you everything.
我们只是胡搞了一下
Well, we fooled around some.
他想再进一步  我也想
He wants to do more, and so do I...
我觉得啦
I think.
只是他比我更有经验
Only he's a lot more experienced than I am,
而我不想像一个傻子
And I do not want to come off as a total freak
-什麽都不懂  　　　　　　　　-先练习一下
- who doesn't have a clue.   -So practice first.
不  据说第一次很可怕
Nah. I've heard horror stories about the first time.
如果男人不够温柔
I mean, if... if the guy isn't careful,
就会很疼
It can be really painful.
那我算是幸运的
Yeah. I was lucky.
布莱恩很温柔
Brian went real slow.
所以  我的第一次  想要
Yeah, well that's why I want my first time
和了解状况的人
to be with someone who...
在一起
knows what it feels like.
像是你
Like you.
她想和你上床吗
She wants you to fuck her?
同志和直女
Gay men and straight girls
这不是世界末日的徵兆吗
Isn't that one of the signs of the apocalypse?
你和女人上过床吗
Have you ever been with a woman?
好几次  我14岁那年
Lots of times. When I was 14,
在夏令营
I had sex with, uh,
和4个女孩上了床
four girls at summer camp.
15岁时  我干了我妈最好的朋友
When I was 15, I had an affair with my mom's best friend.
16岁时
And when I was 16,
和我的几何学老师埃尔斯蒂女士
I made it with Mrs. Elstead, my geometry teacher.
没有啦  开玩笑的
No. No!
你这个小兔崽子
You asshole.
那你怎麽知道你做得到呢
Well then, hon, um... How do you know you can?
因为他现在这个年纪
Because at his age he could rub up
撸着一颗树都能硬
against a tree and get a hard-on.
就我最近刚和女人做过的经验
Having recently made love to a woman, I, um...
我可以给你些建议
I can give you a few pointers.
搞一个粗壮的拉子可不能算是做爱
Banging a bull dyke for Jesus isn't exactly making love.
我倒是曾经和女人做过
I've sort of been with a woman.
-真的  　     -十年级的时候
- You have?   -Tenth grade.
玛莎·格伦迪希帮我口交过
Marsha Grundig gave me a blow job.
不过她向我收了5块钱
Well, she didn't give it to me. She charged me five bucks.
她向每个人都收5块钱
She charged every- body five bucks.
真是感人的回忆
That's a... That's a touching memory.
我知道我会帮达芙妮这个忙
I know I'll be doing Daphne a favour,
可是我还是觉得怪怪的
But I still feel kind of weird about it.
她要你帮她 你该感到荣幸
I think it's a real compliment she asked you to do this.
是啊  代表她很信任你
Yeah, it means she really trusts you.
去吧  贾斯汀
Go to her, Justin.
教她怎麽成为真正的女人
Teach her what it is to be a real woman.
就像曾经有人教过你一样
Like somebody taught you.
小心点
Be careful.
不是吧
Oh, shit!
看来
Well, you were...
你是命中注定逃不掉了啊
bound to run into him eventually.
为什麽偏偏是今晚
Why did eventually have to be tonight?
我该说什麽呢
What do I say?
要说什麽？  当他不存在就好了
Why say anything? Just ignore him.
我应该去道歉
I should go apologize.
不对  你应该待在这回答我
No, you should stay and answer this.
要莱尼呢？ 还是史奎格？
Lenny or, uh, Squiggy?
嗨  布雷克
Hey, Blake, um...
听着  我说过我没拿你的钱
Look, I already told you I don't have your money.
我不是要说这个
That's not why I wanted to talk with you.
我找到皮夹了
Look, I found my wallet.
在艾美特的沙发上
It was in Emmett's couch.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你不知道当时我的感觉
You have no idea how horrible...
简直糟透了
Uh, really horrible I feel.
我知道你现在过得不好
Look, I know you're going through a tough time...
我也知道  在我这麽做以後
Right now, and I realize that after what I did,
你已没理由再相信我  但是
you've got no reason to believe me, but...
如果你有任何需要
If you need anything...
比如  想要一个倾听者  或是
Well, a sympa- thetic ear or...
一个可以哭泣的肩膀  或是
a shoulder to cry on or...
一双客观的眼睛
an objective eye...
那直接拳打脚踢怎麽样
How about throwing in an arm and a leg?
也可以啊
Well, that too...
如果你想要的话
If you want 'em.
就这样吧
All right.
很好  他就穿这个下葬吧
Yeah, this is the one he should be buried in.
破烂乏味  就像他本人
Worn out and dreary, just like him.
你是不是要先拿给你姐看看
Well, do you think you should run it by your sister first?
她要是看到这件又丑又旧的衣服
Hmm, she'd probably see this ugly, old suit
肯定会哭出来
and start crying again.
至少她知道怎麽发泄情感
Well at least she's expressing how she feels.
她只是想引起注意
She's milking it for attention.
-别这麽愤世嫉俗  　　-Claire是个臭婊子
- Don't be cynical.  - Claire is a cunt.
爸爸受不了她  她老公受不了她
Dad couldn't even stand her. Her husband couldn't stand her.
就连她两个儿子也受不了她
Her fucking kids... can't stand her.
既然她那麽没用
So while she's busy being a basket case,
就只好由我来处理这一切
I'm stuck doing everything else,
殡仪馆  墓地
The funeral home, the cemetery...
还有讣文
the obituary.
-我说过我会帮忙  　　　　　　-你想帮忙吗
- Well, I said I would help. - You want to help?
那就看看能不能找到一条
See if you can find a tie
不那麽恶心的领带吧
that's not too offensive, if that's possible.
-布莱恩   -什麽事
- Brian.  - What?
糖包还是方糖好
Packets or sugar cubes?
家里要来那麽多客人
We're going to have a house full of guests.
我不知道大家喜欢什麽
I don't know what people prefer.
我觉得没人会在意这个
I'm sure no one gives a shit.
我妈妈说  通常人们用餐时
Um... My mom says that people
喜欢三合一的糖包
at the diner prefer packets three to one
因为方糖是分开包的
Because the... the... the cubes are individually wrapped,
要是掉在地上了  人们踩上去
and they fall on the floor and people step...
你妈妈最近好吗  迈克
How is your mother, Michael?
她很好  肯尼太太  谢谢您
She's fine, Mrs. Kinney, thank you.
她总是那麽有个性
She was always such a... character.
请替我谢谢她的
Please remember to th-thank her for the...
三明治总汇盘
um, sandwich platter.
我会的
Ah, I will. And, uh...
我很遗憾您丈夫去世了
I have to say I'm sorry for your loss.
谢谢你  迈克
Thank you, Michael.
布莱恩  看到什麽你想要的
Uh, Brian, if you see anything you want,
就带走吧  我打给慈善机构了
just please take it. I've called the goodwill
他们明天就来
and they're coming tomorrow.
这麽快
That was quick.
我受不了东西堆得到处都是
Well, I don't like seeing things lying around, you know that.
比起和我在一起  显然你爸更喜欢这些玩意儿
Your father spent more weekends with that than he did with me.
糖包是吧  好  决定了
Packets. Good. Well, that's decided.
我都不记得在你房间是什麽感觉了
I forgot what it was like at your house.
是啊  所以我总赖在你家
Yeah, that's why I was always over at yours.
有个家伙在我床上吐
A guy threw up on my bed.
-什麽    -我现在住的地方
-What?   -The place where I'm staying.
我今天回去  那些讨厌的混蛋
I... went back there tonight and some tweaked- out asshole...
吐了我一床上
barfed on my bed.
真糟糕
How horrible.
我没法在那住下去了  我
I can't stay there any more. I...
-我真的不能  　　-我没怪你
-I just can't.   -I don't blame you.
我想到你之前说的
Then I thought of what you said, um...
任何事都可以找你帮忙
That I could count on you for anything.
所以你就来这了
So you came here?
我没其他地方可去
I didn't know where else to go.
我很高兴你能来
I'm glad you did.
进来吧
Well, come in.
-你确定吗  　-我很确定
- You sure?  - Sure I'm sure.
欢迎今晚你来住  想的话
You're welcome to stay here tonight, or...
还可以多住几晚
a couple of nights.
行李带了吗
Did you bring your stuff?
嗯　　轻装旅行最好
Well, it's always good to travel light.
快进来
Come on.
我只是想告诉你  我发誓我戒了
I just want you to know, I'm clean. I swear.
我相信你
I believe you.
谢谢
Thanks.
慢着
Um... Look...
我们
Let's, uh...
我们不急着做这个  好吗
Let's not... rush into this, okay?
我是说  我们都需要时间来
I mean, we both need time to, uh...
体会...还有
Comprehend and to, uh...
处理好我们的感受
process how we feel. Hmm?
就是说  我觉得应该
That said, I think it would be...
更恰当地  还有
More... appropriate, not to mention...
负责任地  让我们俩
Responsible... for both of us to, uh...
管他的
Oh, fuck it!
铭记於心  吾等终将归於尘土
Let us remember that we are dust, and we will return to dust.
全能的主  您的儿子死於十字架上
Almighty god, through the death of your son on the cross,
而正是如此  您已为我们征服了死亡
you have overcome death for us.
藉由埋葬和重生
Through his burial and resurrection from the dead,
您已将墓园变成了圣地
you have made the grave a holy place,
并给予我们永生
and restored to us eternal life.
我们为信耶稣的逝者祈祷
We pray for those who died believing in Jesus,
祈祷他能在主的世界重生
and are buried with him in the hope of rising again.
世间万般神灵
God of the living and the dead,
祝福世间所有虔诚的信徒
may those who faithfully believed in you on earth
愿你们在天堂永远快乐
praise you forever in the joy of heaven.
以圣子耶稣的名义
We ask this in the name of Jesus the Lord...
阿门
Amen.
仁慈的上帝  愿杰克和所有死去的虔诚信徒
Through the mercy of god, may Jack and all the faithful departed
都能安息
Rest in the peace of Christ.
阿门
Amen.
在重生的曙光中
In the hope of the resurrection,
让我们的弟兄杰克·肯尼安息吧
Let us leave our brother Jack Kinney to rest in peace.
以圣父圣子之名
In the name of the father and of the son.
阿门
Amen.
克莱尔  振作点好吗
Claire, would you pull yourself together, please?
爸爸死了  妈  我的心也碎了
Daddy died, mother. I am allowed to fall apart.
好吧  你继续心碎去吧
Fine then, fall apart.
我们能走了吗
Can we leave?
我们都在这呆好久了
We've been here for months. years.
你就不能小点声吗
Do you have to be so fucking loud for christ sake?
神父  不好意思
Sorry, Father.
为了布莱恩　我们得留下来
We have to stay for Brian.
他一直不言不语
He hasn't said a word.
连哭都没哭过
Or even cried.
克莱尔给大家做了个好榜样
Well, Claire's doing a bang-up job for everybody.
舅舅  包包里是什麽
What's in the bag, uncle Bri?
你爷爷的脑袋
Grandpa's head.
想看看吗
Do you want to see it?
咱们还是走吧
We better go.
我去抱盖斯
We have to pick up Gus.
还有人等我回去呢
And I, uh, have somebody staying with me,
-所以我想...  　　-真的吗?
-So I should...   -You do?
不会吧
You don't.
各位  不好意思
Oh, excuse me, everyone.
我觉得我们应该缅怀一下
Um, I thought it would be nice...
关於我父亲的点滴
if we all shared some memories of daddy.
神父  从您开始好吗
Uh, Father, would you start?
坦白的说  我和你父亲不熟
I must confess I didn't know him well.
他从没来做过弥撒
He never came to mass.
还有人想说吗
Anyone else?
有一阵子了
It... it was a while ago.
我和布莱恩还在读大学的时候
Brian and I were in college.
他说我身上味道很香
He... he told me once I smelled nice.
哦对了  他还给了我一块薄荷糖
Oh, and then he gave me a mint.
我记得
Uh, I remember...
那时候我刚认识布莱恩
Um, this is just after I'd met brian,
肯尼先生带我们去打保龄球
Mr. kinney took us bowling.
我打的很烂
Um, and I'm a terrible bowler.
布莱恩也不怎麽样
So is Brian.
打完七格我们也只得了九分
I think our score was, like, nine after seven frames.
然後  奇蹟发生了
And, uh, then a miracle happened.
布莱恩扔出了球
Brian rolled the ball and it was
像之前一样朝着沟滚了过去
headed towards the gutter like all the rest,
但是突然它改变了方向
but then suddenly it changed direction.
竟然是个全倒
And there was a strike.
我们激动得跳上跳下
And we were so excited and we were jumping up and down
没有注意到肯尼先生已经
that we didn't realize that Mr. Kinney had come back from the bar
从吧台回来  目睹了这一切
and seen the whole thing.
他跑到布莱恩前面
And he ran over to Brian and he picked him up,
抱着他又搂又亲
and he hugged him and he kissed him,
告诉布莱恩  他是多麽以他为傲
and he told him how proud he was of him.
当然了  布莱恩尴尬的跑掉了
And of course, Brian got all embarrassed and ran off.
那一刻我印象深刻
I guess that moment meant a lot to me
因为我从没有过父爱
because I never had a father and...
我会永远记得那一天
I'll always remember that day
和那个拥抱
and that hug.
迈克  谢谢你
Thank you, Michael.
迈克  这个故事真感人
That was a lovely story, Michael.
是啊迈克  好感人的故事啊
Yeah, Michael, that was lovely.
我也想说说我的一些回忆
It makes me want to share some memories of my own.
那些我们都应该去珍惜的事情
Something we could all treasure.
他知道我妈妈怀了我的那天晚上
At the night that he found out that you were pregnant with me.
他要我妈妈穿上她最漂亮的裙子
He told mom to put on her most beautiful dress,
带她去了城里最高级的餐厅
took her to the most expensive restaurant in town,
给她倒了香槟
poured her a glass of bubbly and then...
他俯下身来
Get this. He leaned over...
对她说  「小琼」
And he said... "Joanie...
「把孩子拿掉吧」
You're getting yourself an abortion because...
「我可不想再有孩子了」
I don't want another fucking kid."
克莱尔  你有什麽要分享的吗
Claire, do you have anything you want to share?
-进来吧  　　　-谢谢
-Come on in.   -Thanks.
把书包放这吧
You can put your backpack over here.
想听点什麽吗
Do you want to listen to something?
喔　随便都好
Oh... yeah, whatever.
随你吧
Whatever you want to hear.
你觉得  要多久时间
So... how long do you think this is going to take?
我也不知道  可能一个小时吧
Um... I dunno. Maybe an hour.
我答应我妈在六点之前回家
'cause I got to be home by 6:00. I promised my mom and
我奶奶今天要过来吃饭
My grandma's coming over for dinner so...
要是你现在不想做
If you don't want to do this then...
不  我想
No... No, I... I do.
你有套子吗
Do you have any condoms?
开玩笑吗
Are you kidding?
我带了点  以防万一
'cause I brought some in case.
还有  润滑剂和杀精乳膏
And, uh, lubricant, spermicidal foam.
你准备的可真足啊
You're really prepared.
我觉得我们该...
I guess we should...
是啊
Yeah.
我觉得该开始了
I guess we should.
某种程度  这也是你第一次
In a way, this is your first time too.
和一个女孩
I mean, with a girl and...
是啊  我们可以
Yeah. We can...
一起来试一下
give it a shot together.
只是完事之後  小芙
Only afterwards, Daph...
我们可别太尴尬
Let's not get weird.
怎样尴尬?
Weird how?
我也不知道  只是...
I don't know, just...
不要那样
Let's just not.
不会尴尬
No weirdness.
感觉如何?
Do you feel good?
很好
Yeah.
说到那个  恐怖的葬礼
Talk about the funeral from hell.
我永远不会忘记
I will always remember
他姐姐尖叫着说  「你吃屎吧」
his sister screaming, "You shit!
「你混蛋」
You shit!"
你看神父在说到和他妈妈
What about Father o'what's-his-face
呆在一个房间时候的脸色
carrying his mother up to her room.
他们呆在一起有  一个小时
They didn't come down for, like, an hour.
你觉得这是真的吗?
Do you think it's really true?
他爸爸的话?
What his Father said?
布莱恩总想一鸣惊人
Ah, you know, Brian's always trying to shock everybody.
不过我有点相信
But somehow I believe it.
你能想像  在这种家庭长大吗?
Can you imagine growing up in that house?
他是怎麽活下来?
How did he ever survive?
谁说他活下来了?
Who's to say he did?
这些东西真好看
Hey, these are kind of nice. yeah.
是啊  要是你想浪漫二人晚餐...
Yeah, they'll make a fabulous centrepiece...
这可是精致的装饰
For your... romantic... dinner for two.
我想用我奶奶留下的那件瓷器
I think I'll use that china my grandmother left me.
嗯  很好啊
Mmmm. perfect.
还有那些高级水晶  (暗指安毒)
Perfect, and, uh, and... and the good crystal.
布雷克肯定会喜欢
I'm sure Blake'll appreciate that.
去你的
Fuck you.
最好是
Excuse me?
我说过他已经不吸毒
I already told you, he's not using.
我们能举手表决一下吗?
Okay, um, can I... can I have a show of hands?
有多少人相信  瘾君子不会再吸毒?
Uh, how many people think the twink is no longer tweaking?
-没人     -你错了吧
- No one. - Yeah, well you're all wrong.
不  小泰  是你错了
No, Teddy, you are.
-我了解              -你才不了解
-Believe me, I know. -You don't know.
-你就是嫉妒            -嫉妒
-You're just jealous.  -Jealous?
嫉妒我终於找到一个人关心我
Jealous that I've actually found somebody who cares about me
想和我在一起
and wants to be with me.
小泰  他在利用你
He's using you, Teddy.
-吸毒的人都这样        -这不是真的
-That's what users do. -That's not true.
你就是不想让我拥有
And you just don't want me to have something
你没有的东西
because you don't have it.
你跟这世界上其他同志一样
You're like every other fag in the world.
你应该道歉
You should apologize.
为什麽?
Ah! For what?
别装傻  他可是你爸
You know damn well. He was your dad.
就算他没有一直善待你
Even though he wasn't always nice to you,
人死後该得到应有的尊重
When you die, you deserve a little respect.
屁话
Bullshit.
要是活着时不尊重人
If you don't earn respect when you're alive,
死了别人才不尊重你
you don't deserve it when you're dead.
不过  你很受人尊敬
Anyway, you were very... respectful.
每个人都被你那小小的回忆
Everyone was very... touched
所深深打动
by your little... memory.
只是你也不记得吧
Only you don't remember shit.
要来点吗?
Want some?
-你闹够了没                           -没有
-Haven't you abused yourself enough?  -No!
那天我打了个全倒...
I got a strike that day...
这个你没记错
You got that right.
我们高兴得又跳又叫
And we were jumping up and down, screaming.
这你也没记错
You got that right too.
然後杰克突然从酒吧回来吓我们一跳
And that's when Jack came back from the bar and surprised us.
但是他并没有抱我
But he didn't hug me.
那只不过你幻想中的理想老爸吧
That was just your "gee, I wish I had a daddy" fantasy.
抱我的是你
You hugged me.
想起来了吗?
Remember?
我还狠狠吻了你
And I gave you a big kiss.
然後他就说
Then that's when he said,
「你们这算什麽  一对小同志吗?」
"what are you, a couple of fuckin' fairies?"
然後我就用力推开了你
And then I pushed you away so hard,
你几乎顺着球道滚了下去
you practically rolled down the lane.
然後我就跑了
And then I ran.
我跑了
And I ran...
然後...  这里真热
And... it's hot in here.
也许不该喝咖啡
Maybe coffee wasn't such a good idea.
待在这陪我
Stay here with me.
好
Okay.
就一会儿
Just for a little bit.
你喝多了
You're high.
对
Yeah.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
-等等       -我是在
- Wait...   -I'm just...
及时行乐
fooling around.
不行  不行
No. no!
等等
Wait.
你不是一直想要吗?  迈克
Isn't that what you always wanted, Michael?
什麽?
What?
酒醉误事大干一场  好忘掉你的混蛋老爸？
A drunken fuck so you don't have to think about your dad?
我从来没想这样
I never wanted that.
你吻功真不赖
You... are the best kisser,
易如反掌(手往下)
hands down.
不  不是  宝贝
No. no-no, sweetheart.
那是个比喻
That's just an expression.
把手放回来
Put 'em... put 'em back up.
很好  很棒
Right. Attaboy.
不好意思...
Excuse me...
亲爱的  我...
Lover, I, uh...
我马上回来  好吗?
I'll be right back. Okay?
千万别.. 别走开
Don't you... don't you go anywhere.
在这儿等我  好吗?
Stay right there, okay?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
不用了
No thanks.
不用什麽?
No thanks what?
我不想跳舞
I don't want to dance.
我也没打算邀请你
I wasn't going to ask.
能让我们单独聊几句吗?
Would you excuse us?
你到底是谁?
Who the hell are you?
我是艾美特·哈尼卡特  泰德·施密特的朋友
I'm Emmett Honeycutt, Ted Schmidt's friend.
我们  嗯...
Yeah, we, um...
我们有天晚上在这里见过面
We met here the other night, when, uh...
就是你抽搐得昏倒在洗手间地板的那晚
You were so tweaked you passed out on the bathroom floor.
我们还忙着送你到急诊室
We had to rush you to the emergency room.
有点印象了吗?
Any of this starting to ring a bell?
我想起来了
I remember now.
那就好  很好
Good! Good for you.
你感觉好些了吗?
So you... you feeling better?
因为泰德让我和他在一起
Now that Ted's letting me stay with him.
这就对了
That's our boy.
那请告诉我  为什麽你现在
So, uh, tell me, why aren't you there, uh,
不是和他一起
talking to him instead of here
而是在这里和毒贩一起呢?
talking to a dealer?
他  他是我朋友
Him? He's just a friend.
亲爱的
Honey...
别跟我鬼扯
Don't bullshit me.
也许泰德
Ted, maybe.
不知道这些事
He doesn't know about these things.
但是我们知道
But, uh... but we do.
没错  我们知道你是怎样
Oh yes, we know what happens
往你这皮包骨的手臂
once you've injec- ted crystal meth
注射冰毒的
into those skinny little arms.
我提醒过他
I tried to warn him...
但是他不听
But he wouldn't listen...
因为他爱你
Because he loves you.
事实上他太爱你了
In fact he loves you so much,
他相信你是纯洁的  想想吧
he believes you're clean. Imagine that.
-我也爱他          -不
-I love him too.   -No.
你爱的是毒品
You love drugs.
那去找毒品好了
So get drugs.
来  我给你钱都行
Here, I will even give you the money.
离开他吧
But leave him alone,
要是你伤了他的心
because if you break his heart,
我就打烂你这张脸
I will break your face.
不好意思
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我的歌来了
they're playing my song.
-嗨    -贾斯汀
-Hey!  -Justin
你来这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我只是想顺道来打声招呼
I just thought I'd drop in and say hi.
-你好  史黛博     -你好  贾斯汀
-Hi, September.   -Hi, Justin.
你们想吃点什麽...
Uh, can I get you something to eat...
我...请客
on the house?
好的  一份巧克力圣代
Oh, yeah. Um, a hot fudge sundae.
我在减肥  要准备参加舞会
I'm on a diet. I gotta get ready for the prom.
好的
Okay.
你们两个是在交往吧?
I suppose you two are going together?
达芙妮  我能跟你聊一下吗?
Daphne, can I talk to you for a second?
来这里
Over here.
-你是不是说了什麽?       -说什麽?
-Did you say anything?   -About what?
哦  那个
Oh... that.
那个啊
Oh, that.
你又没说要保密
We never said it was a secret.
真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
这有什麽  大不了就是
What's so terrible? The worst that can happen
别人认为你是直男
Is people think you're straight.
再说  这样也不错
Besides, it was nice.
我想跟别人分享一下
I wanted to share it with someone.
这样的话  我想好吧
Well then, I guess... it's okay.
我想也许等你下班  我们能一起做些事
I thought maybe we could do something when you get off.
不行  我还有事
Mmm, I can't. I have plans.
什麽事?
What plans?
就是有事
Just plans.
你没跟我提过
You didn't tell me.
你怎麽不跟男朋友一起出去?
Why don't you go out with your boyfriend?
我们分手了
We broke up.
不会吧
You did?
我越想就越觉得
The more I thought about it, the more I realized
我们没什麽共同点
we didn't really have that much in common.
你们不是有  甜蜜的传简讯时光吗?
I... I thought you had amazing i.m. sessions.
没那麽甜蜜  他拼字都会拼错
They weren't that amazing. He can't spell.
而且後来我们就没话题可聊了
And lately we've been running out of things to chat about.
你和我之间就不会这样
That never happens to you and me.
我坐在那等他几个小时
I sat there waiting for him for hours.
也许他忘了
Well, maybe he forgot.
或者有什麽事耽误了
Or had other plans.
我们本来说好一起吃饭
We were supposed to have dinner.
烤肉在炉子里
The roast was in the oven.
酒也冰好了
The wine was chilling.
桌上还摆着鲜花
The flowers were on the table.
最後我还到附近的
Finally I went out driving around.
酒吧和夜店去找他
Checking all the bars, the clubs,
我...    我找不到他
I... I... I could... I couldn't find him.
事情总是这样
Always the way.
你不想遇到某个人
You don't want to run into someone,
却第一个见到他
they're the first person you see.
你想见某个人  却遍寻不着
You want to see someone, and they're nowhere...
我们能回归正题吗?  拜托
Do you mind if we stay on track here? Please?
-当然    -谢谢
- Sure.  - Thank you.
他都没回家
He never came home.
回家?
Home?
也许你该打电话到警察局报案
Well, uh, maybe you should call the police station
-或者医院            -或者太平间
-Or the hospitals.   -Or the morgue.
真谢谢你们的馊主意
Oh, thanks a fucking lot.
我们只是想帮你
Well, we're just trying to be helpful.
那你们就给点有用的意见啊
Well then would you make a helpful suggestion.
瓦特尼先生  请到19号登记处
Mr. Novotny, register 19.
叫我了  先挂了
That's me. Gotta go.
你想要有用的建议吗?
You want a helpful suggestion?
别管他为什麽离开  或是他去哪
Forget about why he left or where he went,
只要感激他终於滚蛋了
And just be grateful that he's gone.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
真後悔打给你们
So glad I called.
我终於明白  为什麽喜欢睡沙发床
Now I know why people sleep on futons.
你干嘛不在百货公司买床垫呢?
Yeah, why didn't you buy a mattress at a department store?
琳赛  亲爱的  甜心
Lindsay, darling, sweetheart,
这问题应该让你回答
You want to field that one?
因为我看到广告  这床垫打五折
Because I saw an ad, 50% off.
好吧  为了省那100块钱
Oh, okay. So in order to save 100 bucks,
你们宁愿冒险弄伤自已的背
You run the risk of permanent back injury.
女人真是奇怪
Women are so fucking weird.
这跟女人有什麽关系?
Why is that a woman thing?
除了缺钱的问题  没有男的
Because no guy, unless he had money issues,
会做这种事
Would do some- thing like that.
用力推
Push.
推  用力推
Push, push, push.
女人对性的看法也很奇怪
You get weird about sex.
我和达芙妮上床之後
After I had sex with my friend Daphne,
她变得超级诡异
She fucking flipped out.
-什麽     -什麽?
-What!?   -What!?
你和达芙妮上床了
You slept with Daphne?
她想把第一次给我
She wanted me to be her first time.
结果呢?
Well how was it?
这个...  她还需要练习
It was... she's going to need practice.
虽然我们之前说好还是做好朋友
Anyway, we said that nothing would change,
不过完全不是那麽回事
And it totally has.
我觉得她爱上我了
I think she's in love with me.
那是因为大多数女人不像男人那样
Well, that's because it's not as easy for most women
把性和爱分得很清楚
To separate love and sex as it is for a man.
是啊
Yeah.
我就是一直看不惯男人这点
That was always my big complaint with men.
特别是还是人家第一次
Especially if it's your first time.
你躺在那
And here you are
允许另一个人进入你的身体
allowing someone to come inside your body.
你会觉得这一生  这一刻和他如此亲近
I mean, you've never felt so close to anyone in your life.
当你意识到  你就...
And before you know it, you're...
爱上这个人了
Falling in love with this person
他让你有一种
Who's made you feel like...
前所未有  无法想像的感觉
You've never even know you could feel.
现在你明白  为什麽达芙妮会爱上你?
So now do you understand why Daphne might be in love with you?
快点  继续推
Come on. Push.
收到你的留言
I got a message at the store
我丢下手边工作
to drop everything.
而且还是在我们卖场
Right in the middle of our big Q
24小时清仓拍卖的时候
24-hour clearance sale.
这是一年里最大的活动
That's the biggest event of the year.
你的鞋
Here's your shoes.
在听到你动情的颂词後
After your touching eulogy,
我决定要对杰克·肯尼
I decided to come and pay my respects
表达我的敬意
To Jack Kinney.
就在我们创下连续洗沟最多次纪录
Where we once bowled the largest number
的那个保龄球馆
Of consecutive gutter balls ever recorded.
怎麽样?  我们为了那老家伙洗一局?
So what do you say? We roll one for the old fuck?
才一个球  不算什麽
That rolls one, almost nothing.
我已经表达敬意  我们走吧
All right, I've paid my respects. Let's go.
等等
Hold on.
没错
That's right.
那该死的娘炮打了全倒
The fuckin' fairies got a strike.
该死的娘炮高兴得跳来跳去
The fuckin' fairies are jumping up and down.
该死的娘炮  要好好庆祝一下
The fuckin' fairies are going to celebrate.
-嗨     -嗨
- Hey. - Hey.
你知道
You know,
三色堇乐团(庞克乐团)的新专辑刚到
the new "Pansy Division" just came in.
想听听吗?
You want to hear?
不了谢谢  改天吧
Oh, no thanks. Some other time.
这衬衫真不错
That's a really cool shirt.
和你眼睛颜色很配
Goes with your eyes.
小芙  你都看过无数次了啊
Daph, you've seen it like a million times.
估计之前没注意到吧
Guess I never noticed.
不过现在注意到了
But I do now.
其实  我过来找你是因为...
Uh, actually, the reason that I'm here...
我本来想e-mail给你
Uh... well, I was going to send you an e-mail
不过我觉得还是当面说比较好
But I thought it would be better if I came in person.
你今晚来我家说好吗?  我是说
Well, why don't you come over tonight? I mean...
我爸妈今晚不在家
My parents aren't going to be home
不
No!
我想  在这里说就好
I mean... it... this is fine.
其实  我只是...
Actually, I just...
想让你明白
I want to make sure that you understand.
我是说  我们只是上过一次床而已
That... I mean, just because we had sex once,
并不表示我们现在是男女朋友
Doesn't mean that we're now boyfriend and girlfriend.
我从没说过我们是啊
I never said we were.
你动不动就打给我  几乎一天打 8次
You're calling me, like, eight times a day.
我才没打给你 8次
I haven't called you eight times.
没错  是11次
You're right. It was eleven.
我还没算上那3次的无声来电
I'm not counting three hang-ups.
还有那个卡片
And that card.
「最高尚的友情像是爱情...」
"Friendship is the highest form of love"...
好啦  我知道了
All right, I get the point.
我是说  你是和很多人都上过床
I mean, when you've slept with as many guys as you have,
所以这次对你来说也只算...
I'm sure that's all that was...
另一次泄慾
another fuck.
我从没说过这只是泄慾
Ah... I never said it was just another fuck.
再说我也没和那麽多人上床
Besides I'm not slept with that many guys.
别在这里讨论这问题  可以吗?
Can we not talk about it here?
我还要工作
I've got to work.
小芙
Daph...
我只是为了帮你
I was doing you a favour.
我们那次是只有性  没有爱的
That's all it was. That's all it was meant to be and...
现在你整个人奇怪到不行
Now you've totally gotten weird,
我们说好不要这样的
which we agreed would not happen.
奇怪的人不是我
I'm not the one who got weird.
自从你认识布莱恩之後
Ever since you met Brian,
你整个人都变了
you've be- come this totally different person.
你跟他去混酒吧  混夜店
You go out with him all the time to bars and clubs.
这根本不是我认识的那个你
It's like I don't even know you.
你变成一个全年无休的同志
You've just become this full- time homosexual.
你怎麽找到我的?
How'd you find me?
我不是说过吗?
Didn't I tell you?
除了当会计之外  我还兼职侦探呢
Besides being an accountant, I'm also a part-time sleuth.
-你好幽默      -是啊
-You're funny. -Yeah.
绝对恐怖乐团(庞克乐团)都嫉妒我的幽默
Sheer Terror piques my wit.
你的手好冷
Your hands are cold.
我想要你回来住
I want you to come back.
不行
I can't.
别和我争
Don't argue.
我会把所有事都搞砸的
I'll screw everything up.
你不会的
You won't.
我会帮你的
I'll make sure of it.
我会照顾你
I'll take care of you.
你还是走吧
I want you to go now.
求求你
Please.
让你睡在这个
And leave you sleeping on this mattress
有人吐过的破床垫?
That some asshole threw up on?
吐这上面的人是我
I'm the one who threw up on it.
我没刷牙
My breath stinks.
我不在乎
I don't care.
那个  歌剧
That... opera...
「茶花女」
"la traviata".
你还没跟我讲结局
You never told me how it ends.
那个谁和那荡妇结婚了吗?
Does what's- his-name marry the slut?
当然
Of course.
违背他混账父亲的意愿
Despite the wishes of his cruel father.
然後...
And...
他们以歌唱为生  唱了很多
They live to sing many...
完美的合唱
Glorious duets.
你  你干什麽?
What are... what are you doing?
上车啦  冷死了
Well, come on. It's cold.
耐心  年轻人  耐心点
Patience, young fella, patience.
又要干嘛?
Now what?
永别了  杰克
So long, Jack.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
22f5fdca275c46b2b46524412c219a75